Robert Schoelkopf Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Artist Files, 1851-1991, undated, Series 1:; (boxes 1-23, 23 linear ft.)
  Files concerning Manierre Dawson document the gallery's representation of the artist's estate and arrangements for the first one-person exhibition of his paintings in New York only a few months before his death in the summer of 1969. The files include correspondence with Dawson in which he discusses preparations for the exhibition, supplies information concerning dates and locations of his paintings, and expresses concerns about his illness. Letters from Dawson's wife, Lillian, written immediately after his death, can also be found here as well as several marked-up copies of the catalog for the 1969 exhibition that includes an introduction written by the artist. The Dawson files document the activities of the partnership formed by Frank J. McKeown, Jr., Dr. Lewis Obi, and Lefferts L. Mabie, Jr., to purchase paintings from the Dawson estate and provide details of how the partnership worked with Schoelkopf as the sole gallery agency for Dawson's paintings. The files also record the distribution of loans and gifts from the partnership to various art institutions.
  More than two feet of records offer detailed coverage of Robert Schoelkopf's interest in Gaston Lachaise and his involvement in the administration of the Lachaise Foundation. Correspondence files chronicle relations among Schoelkopf, John B. Pierce, Jr. (trustee of the foundation), and Felix Landau and record decisions taken regarding publications about the artist, policies for casting and limiting editions of his sculpture, and strategies for promoting Lachaise through exhibitions. The traveling exhibition that opened in September 1967 and was still circulating in 1991 is well documented here, as are other practical concerns such as maintaining accounting and storage records of the artist's work.
  Files relating to Ethel Myers include correspondence with the artist's daughter, Virginia Downes, and document Schoelkopf's handling of Myers's estate and his involvement in exhibitions to promote her work. The files include one undated letter and one copy of a letter from Myers to Downes, dated 1941, and a copy of a letter from Henry McBride to Myers from 1913. Copies of autobiographical notes written by Myers about her childhood, artists she knew, her marriage to Jerome Myers, and the outbreak of war in Europe can also be found here.
  Several files document the appointment and activities of Robert Schoelkopf and Felix Landau as exclusive agents for the sale of works of art from the estate of Elie Nadelman.
  A substantial group of files relating to Joseph Stella chronicle Schoelkopf's involvement with Michael and Sergio Stella, trustees of Joseph Stella's estate, and his representation of the estate from 1963 until 1971, when he withdrew from the position following a dispute over commissions. The gallery continued to consign work from the Stella estate until 1991, and these files contain details of those consignments and reflect Schoelkopf's lifelong commitment to promoting Stella's work.
  Files relating to John Henry Bradley Storrs document Schoelkopf's relationship with the artist's daughter, Monique Storrs Booz, who designated Schoelkopf as the new agent for works of art from her father's estate when her contract with the Downtown Gallery was terminated in 1969. Schoelkopf continued to represent Storrs's work when Monique Storrs Booz died in 1985, leaving the estate in the hands of two of the artist's grandchildren. Details of the gallery's relationship with Noel Frackman, who conducted important research on Storrs, can also be found here. Of additional interest are two sets of photographs attributed to John Storrs: a group of eleven platinum prints (apparently there were originally thirteen), primarily portraits of children, and a group of twenty-seven silver gelatin prints of rural and coastal scenes.
  Another significant component of this series is the number of files documenting the gallery's relationship with various contemporary photographers. Files of correspondence concerning Brassaï contain substantial correspondence with the photographer himself, who frequently wrote to the gallery in French. Records relating to Walker Evans detail Evans's consignments to the gallery and include some letters from him of a more personal nature, such as one describing his observations during a trip to London in 1966. Photographer Giséle è wrote regularly to the gallery, and her letters include detailed descriptions of the processes she employed in printing her work.
  Correspondence relating to Julia Margaret Cameron contains several items of interest including a letter from Cameron dated August 10, 1873, to a Mrs. Way concerning photographs of Way's daughter, and an article on Cameron by Charles Harvard with notes containing biographical details about the photographer.
  Within its artist files the gallery retained a group of files marked "Miscellaneous." These files contain small amounts of material, often only one or two pieces, relating to various artists for whom an individual file was not maintained or who were unidentified. These records are placed at the end of the alphabetical files and contain primarily copy prints, transparencies, and slide transparencies. Material is arranged alphabetically by name of artist, with records relating to unidentified artists placed at the beginning. To retain the alphabetical arrangement various media formats are filed together and dated material is interfiled with undated material, which forms the bulk of the contents.
  The gallery tended to group various types of paper records together with correspondence in a single file. The term "correspondence" in this series, therefore, refers not only to incoming and outgoing letters but also to accounting and consignment records, reports (such as inventory lists), artists' résumés, exhibition lists, price lists, and other miscellaneous notes. In cases where a certain type of "correspondence" was originally filed separately from other material of this kind, and represents a significant amount of material, that material is filed in a separate folder (e.g., Accounting and Consignment Records).
  Generally, arrangement of photographs in this series follows the system outlined under Organization and Arrangement, with some notable exceptions. Photographs of works of art by Gaston Lachaise and Elie Nadelman were originally arranged in a numbering system that is fairly consistent, and this basic original order has been retained. Also, for large groups of photographs of works of art, such as those by Gaston Lachaise, Joseph Stella, and John Henry Bradley Storrs, the gallery filed photographs by media in which the work of art was created; such delineations are reflected in the final arrangement.
  The gallery maintained a collection of negatives, primarily of works of art by artists found in Series 1: Artist Files, in addition to other artists not represented there. There is also a small number of negatives of installation shots. The negatives are arranged alphabetically by artist name, with unknown artists at the beginning, and are stored, for preservation reasons, in containers separate from other records in the series. Negative numbers found on the original sleeves have been transcribed onto the paper enclosures now housing the negatives, so that they may be matched to prints in Series 1: Artist Files, in cases where prints exist. An appendix provides an alphabetical list of artists whose work is represented in the negative collection. In some cases, names of artists are incomplete because of insufficient information on the original negative sleeves.
  See Index 1 for list of artists represented in negatives of works of art
  Index 1: Artists Represented in Negatives of Works of Art
  Albright, Ivan
  [Allston]
  Anderson, Lennart
  Andrejevic, Milet
  Anshutz, Thomas Pollock
  Aponovich, James
  Bailey, William
  Ballaine, G.
  Balthus
  Barye
  Bazelon, Cecile Gray
  Beauchamp
  Beckwith
  Bell, E.
  Bell, Leland
  Bellows, George
  Benton, Thomas Hart
  Bernard
  Birch, Thomas
  [Blauvelk]
  Bluemner, Oscar
  Blythe, David Gilmour
  Bolles, Jesse H.
  Bouvier, August
  Bradford, William
  Branchard, Emile Pierre
  Brassaï
  Bratby, John
  Breckenridge, Hugh H.
  Bricher, A. T.
  Brook, Alexander
  Brown, John George
  Burchfield, Charles
  Burra, Edward
  Carles, Arthur B.
  Carlsen
  Cartier-Bresson, Henri
  Charkow, Natalie
  Chase, William Merritt
  Chiriani, Richard
  Civitico, Bruno
  Clark, Alson Skinner
  Codman, Charles
  Cohen, Frederick
  Cole, Thomas
  Coleman, Glenn O.
  Conrad, Kramer
  Cornell, Joseph
  Cropsey, Jasper Francis
  Currier, [J. Frank]
  Dallman, Daniel
  Dalou, Jules
  Dasburg, Andrew
  Daugherty, James Henry
  [Davidson]
  Davidson, Jo
  Davies, Arthur B.
  Davis, Stuart
  Dawson, Manierre
  Degas, Edgar
  De Kooning, Willem
  Demuth, Charles
  Dewing, Thomas Wilmer
  Dickinson, Preston
  Diederich, William Hunt
  [Dix, Otto]
  Du Bois, Guy Péne
  Duchamp, Marcel
  Duveneck, Frank
  Eaton
  Edmonson, Will
  [Eilshemius]
  Epstein, [Sir Jacob]
  Erlebacher, Martha Mayer
  Evans, Walker
  Fellini
  Fisher, M.
  Fiske, Gertrude
  Flannagan, John Bernard
  Forbes, Charles
  Frazier, John Robinson
  Freckelton, Sondra
  Frieseke, Frederick C.
  Gallatin, A. E.
  Gay, Walter
  Gifford, R. Swain
  Gifford, Sanford Robinson
  Gignoux, R.
  Glackens, William J.
  Gleizes, Albers
  Goodnough, Robert
  Goodwin, Arthur Clifton
  Gorky, Arshile
  Gorsline
  Graham, John
  Graham, William
  Grant
  Grausman, Philip
  Graves, Morris
  Groz
  Guglielmi, Louis
  Guillaume
  Halsall
  Han, Raymond
  Hardy, DeWitt
  Hart, William
  Hartley, Marsden
  Hartman, Bertram C.
  Harvey, Anne
  Hatke, Walter
  Hawthorne, Charles Webster
  Heade, Martin Johnson
  Henri, Robert
  Hill, T.
  Hirst, Claude R.
  Hitchcock
  Hohwiller, L. M.
  Hopper, Edward
  Horton, William S.
  Johnson, David
  Johnson, Eastman
  Johnson, Lester
  Jones, Bern
  Kane, John
  Karfunkle, David
  Kelly, L.
  Kensett, John Frederick
  Klee, Paul
  Klimt, Gustav
  Kline, Franz
  Knaths, Karl
  [Kresch]
  Kruger, Louise
  Kuhn, Walt
  Kuniyoshi, Yasuo
  Lachaise, Gaston
  Laderman, Gabriel
  Lawrence, Jacob
  Lawson, Ernest
  Lechay, Myron
  Leibowitz, Leonard
  Leutz
  Levinson, Abraham F.
  Ligare, David
  Lipchitz
  Luks, George
  MacDonald-Wright, Stanton
  MacMonnies, Frederick William
  Manolo
  Manship, Paul
  Manzu
  Marin, John
  Martin, Homer D.
  Matthiasdottir, Louisa
  Matulka, Jan
  Maurer, Alfred Henry
  McFee Henry
  McIlvain, Isabel
  Melchers
  Metcalf, Willard Leroy
  Mills
  [Morandi, Giovanni]
  Muybridge, Eadweard
  Müller, Jan
  Muller, Lisa
  Myers, Jerome
  Nadelman, Elie
  Nakian, Reuben
  Nevelson, Louise
  Newman, A. L.
  Nick, George Bentley
  Of, George F.
  O'Keeffe, Georgia
  Orozco, José Clemente
  Peterson, Jane
  Peto, John Frederick
  Pfreim, Bernard
  Picasso, Pablo
  Piccolo, Richard
  Pollet, Joseph
  Pollock, Jackson
  Poor, H.
  Powers, Hiram
  Prendergast, Maurice Brazil
  Price
  Prior, William Matthew
  Quin, Langdon
  Raiselis, Richard
  Ream, C. P.
  Reid, Robert
  Richards, William Trost
  Rimmer, William
  Robinson, T. W.
  Rodin, Auguste
  Romero, Orozco
  Rummelspacher
  Russell, Morgan
  Ryan, Richard
  [Ryder, Albert Pinkham]
  Saint-Gaudens, Augustus
  Salemme, Antonio
  Salemme, Attilio
  Sargent, John Singer
  Schamberg, Morton L.
  Schiele, Egon
  Schmidt, Edward
  Schultz, E. N.
  Scott, J. W. A.
  Shahn, Ben
  Shaw, Sidney Dale
  Sheeler, Charles
  Shinn, Everett
  Sklarski, Bonnie
  Sloan, John
  Smith, Hope
  Staples, W. L.
  Steene
  Steichen, Edward
  Stella, Joseph
  Storrs, John Henry Bradley
  Stuart, Frederick, T.
  Suba, Miklos
  Tamayo, Rufino
  Tanguy, Yves
  Tanner, Henry Ossawa
  Taylor, Henry Fitch
  Tillim, Sidney
  Touster, Irwin
  Turner, Helen
  Twachtman, John Henry
  Urness, Scott
  [V., F.]
  Van Beest
  Van Everen, Jay
  Vedder, Elihu
  Vespignani
  Vonnoh, Robert William
  Walcutt, William
  [Wall]
  Weber, Max
  Weir, Julian Alden
  Weiss, George
  Whistler, James McNeill
  Whittredge, Worthington
  Wiesenfeld, Paul
  Woking
  Wood, Thomas Waterman
  Wyant, A. H.
  Wyeth, Andrew
  Zorach, [William]
  - Adams, Pat, General, 1960-1974, 1990, (illustrated letter and a handmade card from Adams) (Box 1)
  - Albright, Ivan, General, 1972, undated (Box 1)
  - Alma-Tadema, Sir Lawrence, General, 1963, undated (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Lennart, General, 1967-1969, 1981, undated (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Walter, General, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Andrejevic, Milet (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1991, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, 1972-1989, undated (Box 1)
    - Photograph of the Artist, undated (Box 1)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Annan, Thomas, Printed Material, undated (Box 1)
  - Anshutz, Thomas Pollock, General, 1980, undated (Box 1)
  - Aponovich, James (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1991, undated, (6 folders; 2 illustrated letters in 1984) (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, Announcements, Catalogs, 1984-1990, undated (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, Clippings, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
    - Photographs of Installations, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Photographs, Miscellaneous, undated, (3 photographs of a house and view of a bay) (Box 1)
  - Atget, Eugéne (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1974, undated (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, 1952-1972 (Box 1)
  - Ault, George (Box 1)
    - Printed Material, 1957-1981, undated (Box 1)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 1)
  - Badger, T., Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 1)
  - Bailey, William (Box 1)
    - Accounting and Consignment Records, 1967-1988 (Box 1)
    - Approval Records, 1972, 1983-1990 (Box 1)
    - Biographical Information, undated (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1983, undated, (12 folders) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1991 (8 folders; illustrated letter in 1990) (Box 2)
    - Exhibition Lists, 1968-1991 (Box 2)
    - Exhibition (1986), Robert Schoelkopf Gallery, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Exhibition (1988), John Berggruen Gallery, 1987-1990, undated (Box 2)
    - Exhibition (1991), Robert Schoelkopf Gallery, 1990-1991, undated (Box 2)
    - Printed Material, Announcements, Catalogs, 1969-1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Printed Materia, Clippings, 1963-1991, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Publication, Burton-Skira, 1985-1987, undated (Box 2)
    - Publication, Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1985-1987 (Box 2)
    - Publication, Rizzoli International Publications, Inc., 1989-1991, undated (Box 2)
    - Photograph of the Artist, undated (Box 2)
    - Photographs of Installation, Alex. Reid & Lefévre, Ltd., [1989] (Box 2)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Balthus, General, 1978, undated (Box 2)
  - Barye, General, 1980, 1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Bazelon, Cecile Gray, General, 1969-1977, undated (Box 2)
  - Beal, Gifford, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 2)
  - Beaton, Cecil, General, 1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Bell, Leland (Box 2)
    - Biographical Information and Exhibition Lists, 1966-1983, undated (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1991, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - Printed Material, Announcements, Catalogs, 1963-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Printed Material, Clippings, 1962-1991, undated (Box 2)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Bell, Temma, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 2)
  - Bellocq, General, 1973-1974, undated (Box 2)
  - Benton, Thomas Hart, General, 1986, 1991, undated (Box 2)
  - Bierstadt, Albert, Photographs of Works of Art, 1966, undated (Box 2)
  - Bigler, Steven, General, 1985, undated (Box 3)
  - Birch, Thomas, General, 1968, undated (Box 3)
  - Birnie, Johan, General, 1962-[1964] (Box 3)
  - Bluemner, Oscar, General, 1967, undated (Box 3)
  - Blum, Robert Frederick, Photographs of Works of Art, 1970, undated (Box 3)
  - Blythe, David Gilmour, General, 1968, undated (Box 3)
  - Bolles, Jesse H., General, 1971, undated (Box 3)
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, General, 1975-1983, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Bouvier, August, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Bradford, William, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Branchard, Emile Pierre, 1927-1967, 1978, undated (Box 3)
  - Brassaï (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1977, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Printed Material, 1938, 1964-1975 (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Bratby, John, General, [1970], undated (Box 3)
  - Breckenridge, Hugh H., General, 1970-1971, undated (Box 3)
  - Bricher, A. T., General, 1967, undated (Box 3)
  - Brown, John George, General, undated (Box 3)
  - Bruce, Patrick Henry, General, 1968, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Bunker, Dennis Miller, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Burchfield, Charles Ephraim, General, 1977, undated (Box 3)
  - Burkhardt, Hans Gustav (Box 3)
    - General, 1979-1985, 1990, undated (Box 3)
    - Work of Art, 1980, (original linoleum cut, 19 of 35) (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Burra, Edward, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Calder, Alexander, General, 1983, undated (Box 3)
  - Cameron, Julia Margaret (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1978, undated (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and Photographs [by J. R. H. Weaver], 1873, 1928, 1963, undated (Box 3)
    - Exhibition Lists, 1968-1974, undated (Box 3)
    - Printed Material, 1967-1984, undated (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Elizabeth, General, 1965-1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Canadé, Vincent, Printed Material, 1959, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Canier, Caren (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Printed Material, 1978-1989, undated (Box 3)
    - Photographs [of the artist's children], circa 1991 (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1978-1991, undated, (1 folder, 1 slide box stored in Box 21) (Box 3)
  - Cantor, Fredrich, General, 1970-1976 (Box 3)
  - Caponigro, Paul, General, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Carles, Arthur B. (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1985, undated (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Cartier-Bresson, Henri (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Printed Material, 1968-1979, undated (Box 3)
  - Charbonnier, Jean-Phillipe, General, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Charkow, Natalie (Box 3)
    - General, 1981-1989, undated (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Chase, William Merritt, General, 1962, 1969-1970, undated (Box 3)
  - Chiriani, Richard (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 3)
    - Printed Material, 1981-1988, undated (Box 3)
    - Photograph of the Artist, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Civitico, Bruno (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Exhibition Lists and Résumés, 1973-1984 (Box 4)
    - Printed Material, 1972-1984, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1973-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Clark, Alson Skinner (Box 4)
    - General, 1916, 1940-1987, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Installations, [1971] (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Codman, Charles, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 4)
  - Coke, Van Deren, General, 1971-1976 (Box 4)
  - Cole, Thomas, General, 1969, undated (Box 4)
  - Coleman, Glenn O., General, 1979, undated (Box 4)
  - Cornell, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, [1963]-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Printed Material, 1965-1990, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 4)
  - Cramer, Konrad (Box 4)
    - General, 1984-1987, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 4)
  - Cumming, Douglas, General, 1972-1974, undated (Box 4)
  - Currier, Charles H., General, 1964-1970, undated (Box 4)
  - Currier, J. Frank (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1985, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 4)
  - Curtis, Edward S., General, 1976-1978, undated (Box 4)
  - Cushing, Barbara (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 4)
    - Printed Material, 1983-1987 (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1983, undated, (1 folder, 0.5 slide box stored in Box 21) (Box 4)
  - Dallman, Daniel (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1991, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Printed Material, 1981-1988, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1979-1991, undated, (1 folder, 0.5 slide box stored in Box 21) (Box 4)
  - Dalou, Jules, General, 1985-1986, undated (Box 4)
  - Dasburg, Andrew, General, 1957-1987, undated (Box 4)
  - Daugherty, James Henry (Box 4)
    - Accounting Records, 1971-1978 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Printed Material, 1971-1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 4)
  - Davidson, Jo, General, undated (Box 4)
  - Davidson, Thyra, General, 1967-1972, undated (Box 4)
  - Davies, Arthur B., General, 1965-1983, undated (Box 5)
  - Davis, Stuart (Box 5)
    - General, 1964-1987, undated (Box 5)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1981-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Dawson, Manierre (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1988, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Exhibition (1981), Robert Schoelkopf Gallery, 1980-1991 (Box 5)
    - Exhibition (1981), Robert Schoelkopf Gallery, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 5)
    - Framing and Restoration Costs, 1981-1984, undated (Box 5)
    - Illinois State Museum Gift, 1981-1985, undated (Box 5)
    - McKeown, Frank, Jr., 1978-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Printed Material, 1967-1989 (Box 5)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - De Casseres, Joe, General, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Decker, Joseph, Photograph of Work of Art, undated (Box 5)
  - Decker, Lindsay, General, 1961-1966, undated (Box 5)
  - Degas, Edgar, General, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - De Kooning, Willem, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 5)
  - Delevoryas, Lillian (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1969, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Printed Material, 1962-1970 (Box 5)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 5)
  - Delgrosso, James, General, 1973-1974, undated (Box 5)
  - Demuth, Charles, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 5)
  - Dewing, Thomas Wilmer, General, 1975, undated (Box 5)
  - Dickinson, Preston, General, 1968-1981, undated (Box 5)
  - Diederich, William Hunt, General, 1988, undated (Box 5)
  - Dove, Arthur Garfield, General, 1968, 1978, undated (Box 5)
  - Driggs, Elsie, Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 5)
  - Du Camp, Maxime, General, 1975, undated (Box 5)
  - Durand, Asher B., General, circa 1978, undated, (copies of material relating to the artist from 1851 to 1854) (Box 5)
  - Duveneck, Frank, General, 1970, undated (Box 5)
  - Eakins, Thomas, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 5)
  - Epstein, Sir Jacob, Photographs of Works of Art, undated (Box 5)
  - Erlebacher, Martha Mayer (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1987, (7 folders) (Box 5)
    - Exhibition Lists and Inventories, 1972-1985, undated (Box 6)
    - Printed Material, Announcements, Catalogs, 1973-1984 (Box 6)
    - Printed Material, Clippings, 1972-1985, undated (Box 6)
    - Résumés, [circa 1973]-1987, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of the Artist, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6)
  - Erlebacher, Walter, General, 1982-1983, undated (Box 6)
  - Evans, Walker (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1977, 1981, 1987, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Exhibition Lists and Inventories, 1971-1974, undated (Box 6)
    - Printed Material, Announcements, Catalogs, 1966-1981, undated (Box 6)